They're both smiling...
(サクラ)二人とも… 笑ってる。
Yeah... He smiled for real for
the first time when he drew that.
あぁ。 その絵を 描いたとき➡
初めて ホントに笑ってた。 心から…。
Smiled from the bottom of his heart.
(ヤマト)こ… これは…！
Wh-What's this...?!
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forgotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenain deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
EVERDAY hereafter is a shining day.
everyday kono saki mo shining day
Unchanging singin', a bright morning smile.
kawarazu singin' hikaru asa no smile
This is the last farewell on funny days.
kore de miosame no funny days
Leaping into the future I see. Go far, dream of my heart.
tobidatsu future mezashita go far kokoro no dream of
I'll go the distance, the endless sky is blue.
i'll go the distance mihatenu sora wa blue
I've hitched a ride on the star ship, this is the best forever trip.
norikonda star ship kore ga saigo no forever trip
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenai deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah, it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
Thank you my friend.
thank you my friend
Ah even now,
aa ano hi no koto
I still remember that day.
ima demo mada oboeteru kara
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah those days that will never come back.
aa mou nidoto sou modoranai days
Woah I'll go the distance!
woah i'll go the distance
Reunion
It was in Sai's bag...
(ヤマト)サイのバッグの中に あった…。
This is an assassination list
that has...
(ヤマト)これは 暗部の者が
己のターゲットを記す 暗殺リスト…。
an Anbu Black Ops member's
own targets recorded...
(ヤマト)いわば ビンゴブックだ。
It's called a Bingo Book.
An assassination list...?
暗殺リスト…？
What are these "X" marks?
この ×印… 何なんです？
In all likelihood,
これは おそらく ターゲットを
すでに 抹殺したという印だろう。
they're marks indicating targets
that have already been eliminated.
Why does Sai have such a thing?
でも…
なんで そんなものを サイが…。
(ヤマト)見ろ。
Look at this...
Th-This is...!
(サクラ)これって…!?
サスケ…!? なんで サイが…!?
Sasuke...
Why does Sai...!
(サイ)忍法 超獣偽画！
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll.
There's no "X" mark on this yet...
まだ ×印が ついていない…。
I get it...
So that's what this is about?
そうか…
そういうことだったのか…。
What do you mean?!
どういうことだってばよ!?
(ヤマト)サイ… アイツの任務は➡
Sai...
His mission wasn't to be a go-between
for Orochimaru and Danzo.
大蛇丸とダンゾウとの パイプ役に
なることなんかじゃ なかった…。
Sai's true classified mission...
サイの本当の… 極秘任務は…。
was to assassinate Sasuke.
サスケの 暗殺だったんだ！
そんなこと…
あるわけねえってばよ！
That could never be!
After all, he said earlier that
he was going to save Sasuke...
だって さっき アイツは
サスケを 助けるって…！
それに！
ホントに… 心から 笑ってた…。
And he really smiled from
the bottom of his heart...
((サイ : 兄さんに 見せたかった…。
This is what I wanted
to show him.
(二人の夢の 絵を…))
The picture of our dreams...
今までと違って アイツは もう…。
Unlike before, he's now...
What if that was all...
それが 全部…。
ナルトを 出し抜くための➡
an act in order
to forestall you, Naruto?
芝居だったとしたら…。
I'm a tool for Danzo-sama.
I don't exist.
((ボクは ダンゾウ様の手足だ。
ボクは 存在しない。
だから ボクに 何を言っても…➡
So no matter what you say to me,
it's pointless...
(無意味なんだよ…))
The owner of this Bingo Book...
この ビンゴブックの持ち主なら
やりかねないよ…。
could indeed be capable
of something like that.
これを 見ろ。
Look at this...
This man in the book
next to Sasuke...
(ヤマト)サスケの隣に載っている
この男…➡
He's a Jonin from
the Hidden Mist...
霧隠れの上忍で 木ノ葉に対し➡
and the man who expressed
a hard-line stance against the Leaf.
強硬姿勢を示していた男だ。
Sai... defeated him, huh...?
サイが… 倒したんですね？
うん…。 簡単に 倒せる相手じゃ
なかったはずだ。
He couldn't have been
an easy opponent to defeat...
(ヤマト)それを
抹殺したということは…➡
The fact that he eliminated him
means that in all likelihood,
he must have resorted
to every possible means.
おそらく
ありとあらゆる手段を講じたはず。
An act in order
to forestall someone...
他人を 出し抜くための芝居などは
日常茶飯事だったろう。
was probably all in
a day's work for him.
笑顔は 目的を達するために…。
A smile is used
to carry out a goal...
((サイ : 騙されたな～。
You tricked me with
your fake smile earlier.
キミの さっきの 作り笑い…。
So that's how you use
a fake smile, huh...?
しかし 作り笑いにも➡
そんな使い方が あるんだね。
覚えておくよ。
I'll remember that.
…オメエは
殴られて なに ヘラヘラしてんだ!!
How can you grin like that
after getting punched?!
厄介事を やり過ごすには
笑顔が いちばん。
A smile is the best way
to get through a tough situation.
(サイ)それが 作り笑いでもね…。
Even if it's a fake smile.
意外と みんな 騙される。
Surprisingly enough,
everyone gets fooled...
(サイ)そう 本に書いてあった))
It said that in a book...
(ヤマト)この
ビンゴブックに 記されている人物を➡
It's quite clear by looking
at each of the people listed...
一人ひとり見れば よく わかる。
in this Bingo Book...
Sai was assigned to the disposal
of people dangerous to the Leaf...
サイは 木ノ葉に対する➡
危険人物の処理に
あたっていたんだ。
And Sasuke is also
one such dangerous person.
そして サスケも…➡
その 危険人物の一人…。
Danzo's goal...
(ヤマト)ダンゾウの目的は➡
was to bury Orochimaru's new flesh...
to bury Sasuke...
大蛇丸の 新たなる肉体…➡
サスケを 葬ることだった…。
そのために サイは
大蛇丸に 近づこうとしたんだ。
In order to do that,
Sai attempted
to approach Orochimaru...
He didn't betray the Leaf.
It was for the sake of the Leaf.
(ヤマト)木ノ葉を
裏切ったわけでは なかった…。
(ヤマト)ただ 木ノ葉のためにと…。
武闘派の 考えそうなことだ…！
That's exactly what one from
a hard-line military faction would think up.
ここで ゴチャゴチャ話してても
しようがねえってばよ…。
There's no point in going on
about that here...
It doesn't matter
what Sai was ordered to do...
サイが どんな命令を受けたとか➡
or what that Danzo guy's
thinking about.
ダンゾウってヤツが
何を 考えてるかなんて➡
どうでもいい！
一刻も早く サイと合流して➡
Meeting up with Sai
as quickly as possible...
and saving Sasuke
is what's important!
サスケを見つけ出すことが 重要だ！
確かに ナルトの言うとおりだね。
It's indeed as Naruto says.
さっき サイのチャクラを感じた。
I felt Sai's Chakra earlier.
We need to go quickly.
急いで 向かうよ！
あぁ！
Right! Got it!
わかったってばよ！
《サクラ : サイが…
サスケ君を 狙ってるのだとしたら➡
If Sai is after Sasuke-kun...
then I'll stop him,
no matter what!
私が… 絶対に 止めてみせる！》
Who's there?
(サスケ)誰だ？
バレちゃいましたか…。
You found me out, huh...?
But... I've already made
the first move.
でも…
ボクは もう 先手をとっている…。
目的は なんだ？
What is your objective?
Danzo-sama's objective is
to bury you...
ダンゾウ様の 目的は…➡
キミを 葬ること。
I'm going to...
ボクは… キミを…。
《サイ…！》
Sai!
...take you back to the Leaf!
木ノ葉へ 連れ帰る！
最も 最初は キミを殺すつもりで
来たんだけど…。
Although at the beginning,
I came here with the intention
of killing you...
((アイツは… 誰よりも オレのことを
認めてくれた 一人だ！))
He's the person who acknowledged me
more than anyone else.
((ナルトは… サスケ君のことを➡
Naruto... thinks of Sasuke-kun
like a brother.
(兄弟みたいに 思ってるから…))
((その仲間を 救うためなら…➡
I'll do whatever it takes
to save him.
なんだって やるさ！
(お前とだって… 組んでやる！))
I'll even team up with you.
((たとえ バラバラに されようが➡
Even if I get chopped up
into pieces,
I'll take Sasuke back
from Orochimaru!
オレは 大蛇丸から…➡
(サスケを
奪い返してやるんだってばよ！))
Sasuke is my friend.
((サスケは… オレの友達だ…。
It's a special bond
I was finally able to make...
(やっと できた…
大切な つながりだ))
I want to protect
his bond with you,
ボクは… 彼が 必死に
たぐり寄せようとしている➡
the one he's desperately trying to
draw closer to.
キミとの つながりってのを…➡
守ってみたいんだ！
つながり…？
Bond...
You interrupted my sleep
for something like that...?
そんなことのために
オレの眠りを ジャマしたのか？
なんだ…!?
What was that?!
It's Sai's Chakra.
サイの チャクラだ。
あっちのほうね！
That way, right?
What was that...?
なんだ!?
《カブト : サスケ君か…。
Sasuke-kun, huh...?
That kid wakes up in
a bad mood, you see...
寝起きは 機嫌が悪いからね…
あの子は…》
うっ… さすがですね。
Impressive...
To think he'd break free
from my Jutsu by force...
ボクの術を強引に振りほどくとは…。
I found him!
《見つけた！》
サクラ！
Sakura!
アンタ ホントは 何が狙いなの？
You!
What're you really after?!
How many times do you have
to betray us until you're satisfied...?
私たちを何回 裏切れば…！
サクラか？
Sakura, huh?
《この声…》
That voice...
サスケ君…？
Sasuke...kun...
サスケ…。
Sasuke...
ナルトか…。
Naruto, huh...?
お前までいたのか…。
So even you were here, huh?
Then is Kakashi also with you?
なら カカシもいるのか？
Sorry, it's not Kakashi-san...
I'm his substitute.
カカシさんでなくて残念だけど
ボクが代理だ。
Team Kakashi will now be taking you
back to the Leaf.
これから カカシ班は
キミを 木ノ葉に連れ帰る。
カカシ班か…。
Team Kakashi, huh?
サイ！ あなた やっぱり！
Sai! I knew it!
ソイツが オレの穴埋めか？
So he's my replacement, huh...?
Some soft one has once again
joined up.
また ぬるいヤツが入ったもんだな。
ナルトと オレのつながりを
守りたいだのなんだの言ってたが。
He said he wanted to protect
the bond...
between Naruto and me, but...
Sai... I thought your mission
was to kill Sasuke-kun-
サイ あなたの任務は サスケ君を…。
(サイ)確かに ボクの極秘任務は➡
My classified mission was indeed
the assassination of Sasuke-kun...
サスケ君の暗殺だった。
けど 命令は もういい。
But I've had enough of orders...
今は 自分の考えで動きたい。
I now want to act on
my own beliefs.
ナルト君が
思い出させてくれそうなんだ。
I think Naruto-kun will get me
to remember...
ボクの昔の気持を…。
my past emotions.
何か とても
大切だった気がするものなんだ。
I kind of get the feeling...
it's something
very important to me.
ボクは キミのことを
よく知らないけど➡
I don't know you very well.
ナルト君やサクラさんが ここまで
必死に キミを追うのには➡
But there must be some kind
of reason why Naruto-kun and Sakura-san...
have pursued you so desperately.
何か訳がある。
キミとの つながりを切るまいと➡
They don't want to sever
their bonds with you...
つなぎ止めておこうと
必死になっている。
They're giving it their all
to secure those bonds.
ボクには まだ
はっきりとはわからない。
I still don't understand it
all that clearly...
けど サスケ君…
キミには わかっているはずだ！
But Sasuke-kun...
you should understand.
ああ… わかっていた。
Yeah... I did understand.
That's why I severed the bonds.
だから 断ち切った！
What a load of crap!
((ふざけんな～っ!!))
((上等だ～っ！
That's just what I want!
うっ!!
《なんで…》
Why?
《あのときから
少しも縮まらない…？
I haven't narrowed the gap at all
since back then.
この差は なんだ？》
What's up with this difference?
(イタチ)お前は 弱い。
You're weak.
なぜ弱いか…
足りないからだ…。
You're weak...
because you don't have enough...
憎しみが…。
hatred.
(うわぁぁぁぁっ!!))
オレには 別のつながりがある…。
I have different bonds...
兄との憎しみっていう
つながりがな…。
Bonds of hatred...
with my older brother.
The clouds
drift accross
a distant sky,
The clouds
drift accross
a distant sky,
sora wa haruka
kumo wa nagarete
Far, far, far away,
beyond the horizon.
tooku tooku tooku
ni kogaretemo
Where will I go
from here and
what do I want?
Where will I go
from here and
what do I want?
doko o mezashite boku
wa fumidasu no ka
It's time to break
through my
fears and doubts.
It's time to break
through my
fears and doubts.
mayoi o ima
furikitte
Even though
I have a destiny
that I can't
escape from,
Even though
I have a destiny
that I can't
escape from,
nigeba no nai
unmei demo
I'm searching
for tomorrow.
asu o sagashite
Because the bonds
of friendship
keep me strong.
Because the bonds
of friendship
keep me strong.
boku o tsuyoku
suru no wa
nakama no kizuna
boku o tsuyoku
suru no wa
nakama no kizuna
Awaken the wild
side and let loose
the feelings!
Awaken the wild
side and let loose
the feelings!
mezamero yasei
afuredashita
kanjou
mezamero yasei
afuredashita
kanjou
Hidden within
my heart as I
smile recklessly.
Hidden within
my heart as I
smile recklessly.
mune ni himete
gamushara
no egao de
mune ni himete
gamushara
no egao de
And it's only when
I shout that the
truth is echoed.
And it's only when
I shout that the
truth is echoed.
sakebigoe wa
woah woah
shinjitsu dake
hibiku darou
sakebigoe wa
woah woah
shinjitsu dake
hibiku darou
My heart burns
and I'll hold on
to your hand.
My heart burns
and I'll hold on
to your hand.
kokoro moyase
soshite te o
tsunagou
kokoro moyase
soshite te o
tsunagou
今日のテーマは ナルトをめぐる
「つながり」についてよ。
If we're gonna
pursue those
eternal desires.
If we're gonna
pursue those
eternal desires.
yume ni
kometa eien
no negai o
yume ni
kometa eien
no negai o
(サクラ)生い立ちゆえに
誰にも認められず➡
Your prayer will
be granted,
motomeru nara
woah woah
孤独だったナルトを
初めて認めてくれた人…➡
Because the light
you seek lies there.
sagashiteru
hikari wa kitto
soko ni aru sa
sagashiteru
hikari wa kitto
soko ni aru sa
それは イルカ先生。
ナルトが 初めて手にした
大切な つながりね。
そして 仲間という つながりを
作るきっかけとなる➡
私たち カカシ班が結成された。
Awaken the
beast within!
mezamero
yasei
Hmph,
It's you...
At last,
they meet again.
Finally.
その後のナルトは 持ち前の
負けん気と がんばりで➡
Next Episode
You've severed our bonds?
里のみんなにも認められ➡
次々と つながりの輪を
広げていったのよ。
If that's what you say,
then why didn't you kill me
back then?!
人と人とを結ぶ つながりの糸は
時を経るに従い➡
You think that would sever it,
Sasuke?!
It's not that I couldn't sever
the bond shared with you.
太く 力強くなっていく。
It's just that your life
was spared back then...
一度
この糸を持ってしまった人間は➡
because of my passing whim.
相手のことを理屈抜きで
放ってはおけない。
And because of my passing whim,
you will now lose your life.
イルカ先生の言葉だけど
心に残る言葉よね。
みんなも 自分の
つながりの糸を➡
The Power of Uchiha
Next Time: "The Power of Uchiha"
探してみてね。
NINJA ACADEMY
SPECIAL CLASS
"BONDS"
The theme for today is
the bonds surrounding Naruto.
Due to his background, Naruto was isolated
in his early life...
and nobody would acknowledge him.
Iruka-sensei was the first one
to acknowledge him.
This was the first important bond
Naruto acquired.
And then Team Kakashi was formed,
which served as the chance for him to
create the bond known as friendship.
After that, Naruto would be acknowledged
by everyone in the village
due to his inherent competitive spirit
and tenacity.
He would continue to expand
that circle of bonds.
The threads of bonds
that connect people
grow thicker and stronger
with the passage of time.
Once a person comes into
possession of these threads,
without a need for convincing,
they will not forsake someone.
It's a line borrowed from
Iruka-sensei,
but they are unforgettable,
aren't they?
I hope you will all try finding
your own threads of bonds.